Toni Morrison Papers, 1908-2017: Finding Aid C1491
mss EADs that duplicate ones in Manuscripts
- Printed Materials, 1908-2016; 34 boxes
  - Toni Morrison Editions and Translations, 1970-2012; 21 boxes
    - Finnish Editions, 1978-2004; 1 box
      - Tervanukke, 1982; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 4)
      - Minun kansani, minun rakkaani, 1988; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 5)
      - Jazz, 1994; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 6)
      - Sinisimmät silmät, 1994; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 7)
      - Sula, 1995; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 8)
      - Soittoa pimeässä, 1996; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 9)
      - Minun kansani, minun rakkaani, 2004; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 10)
      - Rakkaus, 2004; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 11)
      - Jazz, 2004; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 12)
    - Italian Editions, 1981-2004; 3 boxes
      - Canto di Salomone, 1981; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 13)
        Milano: Gruppo Editoriale Fabbri Bompiani
      - Canto di Salomone, 1981; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 1)
      - L'isola delle illusioni, 1982; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 2)
      - Amatissima, 1988; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 3)
        Edizioni Frassinelli
      - Sula, 1991; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 4)
        Milano: Edizioni Frassinelli
      - Sula, 1991; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 5)
      - Jazz, 1993; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 6)
      - Jazz, 1994; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 7)
      - Amatissima, 1994; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 8)
      - Giochi Al Buio, 1994; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 9)
      - L'Occhio Piu Azzurro, 1994; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 10)
      - Canto di Salomone, 1995; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 11)
      - Jazz, 1996; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 12)
      - Amatissima, 1996; 1 folder (Box 209, Folder 13)
      - L'Isola delle Illusioni, 1998; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 1)
      - Amore, 2004; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 2)
    - French Editions, 1972-2008; 2 boxes
      - L'oeil le plus bleu, 1972; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 3)
        Paris: Editions Robert Laffont
      - La Chanson de Salomon, 1985; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 4)
        Paris: Acropole
      - Tar Baby, 1986; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 5)
      - Beloved, 1989; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 6)
        Paris: Christian Bourgois Editeur
        Some water damage
      - Beloved, 1990; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 7)
      - Beloved, 1991; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 8)
      - Sula, 1992; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 9)
      - Le Chanson de Salomon, 1993; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 10)
        Paris: Belfond
      - Beloved, 1993; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 11)
      - Jazz, 1993; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 12)
      - Jouer Dans Le Noir, 1993; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 13)
      - Discours de Stockholm, 1994; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 14)
      - Sula, 1994; 1 folder (Box 210, Folder 15)
      - Sula, 1994; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 1)
      - L'oeil le plus bleu, 1994; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 2)
      - Playing in the Dark, 1995; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 3)
      - Jazz, 1995; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 4)
      - L'oeil le plus bleu, 1996; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 5)
      - Le Chant de Salomon, 1996; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 6)
      - Tar Baby, 1996; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 7)
      - Le Chant de Salomon, 1997; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 8)
      - Tar Baby, 1997; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 9)
      - Paradis, 1998; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 10)
      - Love, 2004; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 11)
      - Love, 2008; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 12)
        Christian Bourgois Editeur: Paris
      - La Cigale ou La Fourmi?, 2004; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 13)
        Casterman
    - Polish Editions, 1980-2005; 2 boxes
      - Pieśń Salomonowa, 1980; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 14)
        Warszawa: Czytelnik
      - Umiłowana, 1996; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 15)
        Warszawa: Świat Książki
      - Jazz, 1996; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 1)
      - Raj, 1999; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 2)
        Warszawa: Prószyński i S-ka
      - Miłość, 2005; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 3)
    - Slovenian Editions, 1977-2004; 1 box
      - Salomonova pesem, 1977; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 4)
        Pomurska založba
      - Ljubljena, 2004; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 5)
        Delo d.d.
    - Slovakian Editions, 1981-1996; 1 box
      - Pieseň o Šalamúnovi, 1981; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 6)
        Bratislava: Smena
      - Nejmodrejší Oči, 1986; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 7)
        Slovensky Spisovatel
      - Džez, 1996; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 8)
        Bratislava: Slovensky Spisovatel
    - Czech Editions, 1983-1996; 1 box
      - Nejmodrejší Oči, 1983; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 9)
        Praha: Odeon
      - Velmi Modré Oči, 1995; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 10)
        Praha: Hynek
      - Jazz, 1995; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 11)
        Praha: Knižní Klub
      - Milovaná, 1996; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 12)
        Praha: Hynek Knižní Klub
    - Arabic Editions, 1989; 1 box
      - Beloved, 1989; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 13)
        Al-Ahram Publishing House: Cairo
    - Hebrew Editions, 1994-2004; 1 box
      - Beloved, 1994; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 14)
        Printed in Israel
      - Jazz, 1995; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 15)
      - The Bluest Eye, 1996; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 16)
      - Love, 2004; 1 folder (Box 212, Folder 17)
    - Korean Editions, 1983-2007; 2 boxes
      - Sula, 1983; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 1)
        Seoul: Eulyoo
        With card from USIA, dated 2/9/1984.
      - Jazz, 1992; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 2)
        Seoul: Munhak Segye-Sa Publishing Co.
      - The Big Box, 2000; 1 folder (Box 216, Folder 3)
        Seoul: Munhakdongne Publishing Co.
      - Paradise, 2001; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 3)
        Seoul: Dulnyouk Publishing Co.
      - Jazz, 2001; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 4)
      - Beloved, 2003; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 5)
      - Song of Solomon, 2004; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 6)
      - Love, 2006; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 7)
      - Tar Baby, 2007; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 8)
    - Japanese Editions, 1970-2006; 2 boxes
      - The Bluest Eye, 1970; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 9)
        Tokyo: Asahi Shumbun Sha
        With pamphlets.
      - Sula, 1979; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 10)
        Tokyo: Hayakawa Publishing Co.
      - Song of Solomon, 1980; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 11)
        Tokyo: Hayakawa Publishing Inc.
      - Tar Baby, 1981; 1 folder (Box 213, Folder 12)
      - Beloved, 1987; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 1)
      - Playing in the Dark: Whiteness and the Literary Imagination, 1992; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 2)
      - Song of Solomon, 1994; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 3)
      - The Bluest Eye, 1994; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 4)
      - Jazz, 1994; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 5)
      - Tar Baby, 1995; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 6)
      - Sula, 1995; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 7)
      - Love, 2005; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 8)
      - The Toni Morrison Encyclopedia, 2006; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 9)
        Yushodo Press Co., Ltd.
        With postcard from Konomi Ara.
    - Chinese Editions, 1990-2008; 2 boxes
      - Beloved, 1990; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 10)
      - Beloved, 2000; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 11)
        Foreign Language Teaching and Research Press
      - Beloved, 2003; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 12)
        The Commercial Press Ltd.
      - Jazz, 2003; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 13)
      - Paradise, 2004; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 14)
        The Commercial Press, Ltd.
      - Paradise, 2004; 1 folder (Box 214, Folder 15)
        Shanghai Translation Publishing House
      - Song of Solomon, 2004; 1 folder (Box 215, Folder 1)
      - The Bluest Eye, 2007; 1 folder (Box 215, Folder 2)
      - Song of Solomon, 2008; 1 folder (Box 215, Folder 3)
        Contains note written inside cover from Tung-jung Chen to Professor Morrison, dated February 1, 2009.
      - Sula, 2008; 1 folder (Box 215, Folder 4)
    - Greek Editions, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - ΤΖΑΖ, 1994; 1 folder (Box 215, Folder 5)
      - ΓΑΛΑΖΙΑ ΜΑΤΙΑ, 1995; 1 folder (Box 215, Folder 6)
  - Books by Other Authors, 1936-2008; 6 boxes
    Books by other authors; in some cases annotated by or inscribed to Toni Morrison.
    Arranged by author.
    - Speedboat, 1976; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 1)
      Note inside front cover.
    - The Greatest: My Own Story, 1975; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 2)
      Uncorrected First Proof
    - A Documentary History of the Negro People in the United States, 1963; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 3)
      New York: The Citadel Press
      Front cover unattached
    - Those Bones Are Not My Child, 1999; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 4)
    - Deep Sightings and Rescue Missions, 1996; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 5)
    - Gorilla, My Love, 1972; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 6)
    - The Salt Eaters, 1980; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 7)
      New York: Vintage Books
    - The Sea Birds are Still Alive, 1977; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 8)
      Annotated by Toni Morrison.
    - Paixões Crioulas, 1987; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 9)
      Sao Paulo: Autoria Quilombhoje
      Inscribed to Toni Morrison
    - Henderson The Rain King, 1985; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 10)
      New York: Viking Penguin Inc.
    - I Ain't Chicken, 1994; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 11)
      Cincinnati: Authentic Expressions
      Note from author written in front cover
    - O Estranho, 1984; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 12)
      Roswitha Kempf/Editors: Sao Paulo
    - O Negro Escrito, 1987; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 13)
      Sao Paulo: Imprensa Oficial do Estado
    - A Mulher Escrita, 1989; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 14)
      Rio de Janeiro: Casa-Maria Editorial
    - Melville: A Collection of Critical Essays, 1962; 1 folder (Box 217, Folder 15)
      Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall, Inc.
    - Home Before Dark, 1984; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 1)
      Boston: Houghton Mifflin Company
      Uncorrected Page Proofs, with annotation.
    - A Noite Não Pede Licença, 1987; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 2)
      Sao Paulo: Roswitha Kempf/Editores
    - Outras Miragens: Miragem de Engenho, 1989; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 3)
      Sao Paulo: Confraria do Livro
    - Constelações, 1990; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 4)
      Sao Paulo: Ebral (Empresa Brasileira de Engenharia Especializada Ltda.)
    - Alternativas Para Combater o Racismo, 1989; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 5)
      Salvador: Nucleo Cultural Afro Brasileiro
    - Schwarze Poesie/Poesia Negra, 1988; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 6)
      St. Gallen/Koln/Sao Paulo: Edition dia
    - It's Like This, 1980; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 7)
      Gardena, CA: Printing Impressions
    - Beyond the Fields: Slavery at Middleton Place, 2008; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 8)
      Middleton Place Foundation
    - Jonoah and The Green Stone, 1976; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 9)
      "Toni Morrison" written in flyleaf in Morrison's hand.
    - "Beloved, she's mine": Essais sur Beloved de Toni Morrison, 1993; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 10)
      Paris: Cetanla
    - Absalom, Absalom, 1987; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 11)
    - The Portable Faulkner, 1966; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 12)
      New York: The Viking Press
    - Was Huck Black? Mark Twain and African American Voices, 1993; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 13)
      New York: Oxford University Press
    - The Bloodworth Orphans, 1977; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 14)
    - Two Wings to Veil My Face, 1983; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 15)
    - Two Wings to Veil My Face, 1988; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 16)
      Chicago: Another Chicago Press
      Foreword by Toni Morrison.
    - Cotton Candy on a Rainy Day, 1978; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 17)
      New York: William Morrow and Company, Inc.
      Uncorrected advance proofs.
    - A Cor da Ternura, 1989; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 18)
      Sao Paulo: FTD
    - The Black List, 2008; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 19)
      New York: Atria Books
    - Lost Atlanta, 1981; 1 folder (Box 218, Folder 20)
      Inscribed to Toni Morrison from Mimi Gross, dated September 1, 1998.
    - The Sociology of Art, 1982; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 1)
      Chicago: University of Chicago Press
      Annotated by Toni Morrison
    - American Hieroglyphics: The Symbol of the Egyptian Hieroglyphics in the American Renaissance, 1980; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 2)
      "Toni Morrison Princeton" written in flyleaf in Morrison's hand.
      Baltimore: The John Hopkins University Press
    - Two Novels: Corregidora & Eva's Man, 1975; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 3)
      Owned by Toni Morrison ("Toni Morrison" written in flyleaf in Morrison's hand).
    - Labor of Love, Labor of Sorrow: Black Women, Work, and the Family from Slavery to the Present, 1985; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 4)
      New York: Basic Books, Inc.
      Uncorrected Page Proof, with annotations by Toni Morrison.
    - Rise, 2001; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 5)
      Chicago: Tia Chucha
      Signed by the author. Note from author's partner on cover.
    - Canto à Negra Mulher Amada, 1986; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 6)
      Sao Paulo: Edicao do Autor
      Inscribed to Toni Morrison.
    - Annie John, 1985; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 7)
      New York: Farrar Straus Giroux
    - Balm in Gilead: Journey of a Healer, 1988; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 8)
      Reading, MA: Addison-Wesley Publishing Co.
      Advance proofs.
    - Nowheresville, Everywhere, Earth, 2008; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 1)
      Bloomington, IN: AuthorHouse.
    - Melanina, 1988; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 9)
      Sao Paulo: Joao Scortecci Editoria
    - Asas Do Meu Corpo: Prazer, 1987; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 10)
      La Edicao: Sao Paulo
    - African Religions and Philosophy, 1970; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 11)
      New York: Anchor Books
    - Redburn, White-Jacket, Moby-Dick, 1983; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 12)
      New York: Literary Classics of the United States
    - Truth: Red, White & Black, Vol. 1, No. 1-2, 2003; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 13)
      New York: Marvel Comics
    - The Book and the Brotherhood, 1988; 1 folder (Box 219, Folder 14)
      Viking: New York
      Unrevised and unpublished proofs, signed by Toni Morrison on title page.
    - Reading Race, 1988; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 1)
      "Toni Morrison Princeton 1990" written in flyleaf in Morrison's hand.
      Published by The University of Georgia Press.
    - The Land in the Day, 1978; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 2)
      Austin, TX: New Latin Quarter Editions
    - El silencio y sus Filos, 2002; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 3)
      New York: Editorial ARCAS
    - Complete Tales and Poems of Edgar Allan Poe, 1975; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 4)
      Handwritten annotations by Toni Morrison.
    - Dear Diego, 1986; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 5)
      Uncorrected Proof
    - Malungos and Milongas, 1988; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 6)
    - The Wages of Whiteness, 1991; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 7)
      Toni Morrison nameplate on flyleaf; highlighting marks.
      New York: Verso
    - James Rosenquist at Gemini, 1983; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 8)
      Los Angeles: Gemini
    - Truman Capote: The Story of His Bizarre and Exotic Boyhood by an Aunt Who Helped Raise Him, 1983; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 9)
      Uncorrected advance proof, annotated by Toni Morrison.
      Slight water damage
    - Draga, 1989; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 10)
      Belo Horizonte, Brazil: Imprensa Official
    - Her First American, 1985; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 11)
      Toni Morrison's name signed inside
    - Tra Pittura, Racconto e Poesia, 2006; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 12)
      Noubs Narciso argento
    - Betsey Brown, 1985; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 13)
      New York: St. Martin's Press
    - Nappy Edges, undated; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 14)
      Uncorrected advance bound proofs
    - Lectures in America: The Great Writer Discusses Her Concepts of Art, 1975; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 15)
    - Three Lives, 1936; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 16)
      A Modern Library Paperback.
      Cover unattached
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, The Minister's Wooing, Oldtown Folks, 1982; 1 folder (Box 220, Folder 17)
      Published as The Library of America edition by Literary Classics of the United States.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, 1967; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Farewell Song, 2005; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 2)
      India: Srishti Publishers and Distributors
      Inscribed to Toni Morrison by the author
    - My Soul Has Grown Deep, 2001; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 3)
      Philadelphia: Running Press
    - Some Sweet Day, 1973; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 4)
      Uncorrected first proof; annotated by Toni Morrison.
  - Manuscripts by Other Authors, 1982-2016; 4 boxes
    Includes manuscripts by other authors, often inscribed to Toni Morrison.
    - Scarlet Gravel Excerpt, 2008; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 5)
    - How to Overcome Depression with Feathers (Or a Trope about Hope and How It Will Defeat Poverty), 2015; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 2)
    - Exclusion and Hierarchy, undated; 2 folders (Box 221, Folder 6-7)
    - The Darktown Strutters, 1982; 2 folders (Box 221, Folder 8-9)
    - The Price of Admission, 2000; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 10)
    - The Black Notebooks, 1987; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 11)
    - George Anderson: Notes for a Love Song in Imperial Time, 2012; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 12)
    - War Stories, 2011; 1 folder (Box 221, Folder 13)
    - Love Medicine, 1984; 2 folders (Box 221, Folder 14-15)
    - The Memoirs of Joubert Jones, undated; 2 folders (Box 221, Folder 16-17)
    - The First Fig Tree and Other Stories, 1986; 2 folders (Box 222, Folder 1-2)
    - "Attention, MOVE! This is America!", 1987; 1 folder (Box 222, Folder 3)
    - The Making of Black Intellectuals: Studies on African-American Intelligensia, undated; 1 folder (Box 222, Folder 5)
    - Reclaiming Rose, 2016; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 3)
    - Untitled Manuscript, 2015; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 4)
    - Powers of Charlotte, 1987; 1 folder (Box 222, Folder 6)
    - Ireland's Necklaces, 2016; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 5)
    - Untitled Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 222, Folder 7)
    - When Rocks Dance, 1986; 2 folders (Box 222, Folder 8-9)
    - Looking for Lorraine, 1986; 1 folder (Box 332, Folder 3)
    - The Swallow's Tears, Undated; 3 folders (Box 222, Folder 10-12)
    - Conjuring: Black Women, Fiction, and Literary Tradition, 1985; 2 folders (Box 222, Folder 13-14)
    - Fiscal Pear and Shimmer in The Call of River Whale, undated; 1 folder (Box 222, Folder 15)
    - Love Must Not Be Forgotten, 1986; 1 folder (Box 222, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 6)
  - Academic Articles and Papers, 1908-2016; 3 boxes
    Includes academic articles and papers by other authors, often inscribed to Toni Morrison.
    - "Black Writing, White Reading: Race and the Politics of Feminist Interpretation", 1993; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 1)
      Reprinted from Critical Inquiry 19, published by The University of Chicago.
    - "The Chorus in Greek Life and Drama", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 2)
    - "Creating a Feminist-Communitarian Romanticism in Beloved: Toni Morrison's New Uses for Blake, Keats, and Wordsworth", 2000; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 3)
      Inscribed to Toni Morrison from Martin Bidney, dated October 13, 2000.
      Photocopy of article published in Papers on Language and Literature 36.
    - "Aesthetic Activity", 1999; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 4)
    - "The Man with the Sword: Edouard Manet's Double-Edged Works", 1994; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 5)
      Excerpt from Nineteenth Century French Studies, Volume 22, Number 3 & 4.
      Inscribed to Toni Morrison from Beth Archer Brombert.
    - "The Flying African and the Flying Greek: Classical Mythology in Toni Morrison's Song of Solomon", 1983; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 6)
    - Introduction to Beloved, undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 7)
    - Untitled Paper, undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 8)
    - "Circles of Glory and Sorrow: A Talk Given to the Combined Women's Studies Sections, The Symposium on Love ", 1981; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 9)
    - "Give Me Some Skin: The Charisma of the Aztec Warrior", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 10)
      With Morrison's handwritten notes on final page.
    - Waiting for the Dawn: Mircea Eliade in Perspective Excerpt, undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 11)
    - " Negative Liberties: Morrison, Pynchon, and the Problem of Liberal Ideology by Cyrus R.K. Patell", 2002; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 12)
      Photocopied excerpt of South Atlantic Review Volume 67, Number 4.
      Inscribed to Toni Morrison from Marc Conner.
    - "A Maverick in Academia: The Dark Lady of Deconstruction. Interview with Avital Ronell", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 13)
      Annotated.
      Photocopied excerpt of Frisko.
    - "From Fragmentation to Fulfillment: Black Feminist Literary Criticism", 1981; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 14)
    - "What is a Minor Literature?", 1986; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 15)
      Photocopied excerpt from Kafka: Toward a Minor Literature (Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press).
    - "Claudia's Blues Performance in Toni Morrison's The Bluest Eye ", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 16)
    - "The American Revolution as Legitimating Social Narrative", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 17)
    - "Toni Morrison's Sula: An Inverted Inferno", 1988; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 18)
      Photocopied excerpt from High Plains Literary Review Vol. III, No. 1.
      With letter from John Domini dated March 9, 1992.
    - "Writing a Body for Memory: The Rescue of History's Fiction in Toni Morrison's Beloved ", 1988; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 19)
    - "Flesh that Dances: Toni Morrison and Beloved ", "Slavery, Science and Somalogics", and "Races and Chains: The Sexuo-Racial Matrix in Ulysses ", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 20)
    - 'HOO, HOO, HOO': Some Episodes in the Construction of Modern Whiteness, 1995 December; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 21)
      Note from author on cover.
      Article in the journal of American Literature, Volume 67, Number 4.
      Durham: Duke University Press
    - "From Inside-Out: The Clarence Thomas-Anita Hill Media Confrontation", 1993; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 22)
      With letter from W. Theodore Dürr dated February 8, 1993.
    - "Aspects of African History, African American Politics and Caribbean Culture", 1998; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 23)
    - "The Moment of Race in Renaissance Studies", 1996 March; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 24)
      With related review article from The Art Bulletin and letter from Peter Erickson dated March 23, 1996.
    - "Music and the Allegory of Memory in Margaret Garner ", 2006; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 25)
      Published in MFS Modern Fiction, Volume 52 Number 2.
    - "To Embrace Dead Strangers: Toni Morrison's Beloved ", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 26)
      Photocopied excerpt from Mother Puzzles: Daughters and Mothers in Contemporary American Literature.
      With photocopied annotations.
    - "Slavery's Psychological Wounds and the Slave-Child's Ghost as Symbolic Character", 2009; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 27)
      With letters from Wendy Stallard Flory, dated June 6 and June 16, 2009.
    - "Feminism, Racism and the Social Geography of Childhood", 1990 January; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 28)
    - " The Bluest Eye: A Story For All", 1991; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 29)
      With letter from Pauline J. Funk, dated October 12, 1991.
    - "The Man of Letters in a Closed Shop", 1991 November 15; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 30)
      Published in the Times Literary Supplement.
    - "Jean Toomer and Toni Morrison: Mythic Creators", 1981; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 31)
    - "The Solipsistic vs. Multiple Perspective in Contemporary Fiction: Male vs. Female Writers", undated; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 32)
    - "Masterpiece Theatre: An Academic Melodrama", 1991; 1 folder (Box 223, Folder 33)
      Reprinted from Critical Inquiry 17, published by the University of Chicago.